

CONTACT

317.426.0847

tylermitchellisawesome@gmail.com

http://tylermitchell.github.io

PROFILE

Hi, I'm Tyler. I create new things and utilize automation and Outside-The-Box thinking to help solve your problems.

I enjoy developing rich multimedia web applications and data driven visualizations. In my work I research and utilize the latest technology and automation to maximize my productivity and pride myself on being efficient. When an application seems difficult to implement, often you just need to step back and look at different tools or technology to save yourself a lot of time and effort. I enjoy learning new tools and ways of thinking and do so very rapidly.

In my personal time, I find myself gravitating towards web app development and game design in my spare time. I participate in Global Game Jam, among other game jams, throughout the year. I also enjoy plenty of board games, Magic: The Gathering, No Man's Sky, and playing with my cat, Beatrice.

EDUCATION

Eleven Fifty Academy

September 2020-December 2020

Web Development

12-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training.

IUPUI

2008-2012

Computer Science

Completed 90 credit hours towards a B.S. degree, but left due to a family health emergency.

SKILLS

JavaScript (ES8), HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, PERN
Stack, React, D3js, SQL, NodeJS, Postgres,
Express, Unity3D, C#, Git, HTTP, Web App
Development, Full-Stack Development
Analytical Thinker, Adaptable, Dependable,
Organized, Self-Motivated, Efficient

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Security Guard

Securitas, August 2020-Current

- * Control Access to a large warehouse with thousands of employees.
- * Detect and report theft, hostility, and property damage.

Inventory Control Specialist

Pitney Bowes, June 2019-December 2019

- * Generated optimal walking paths to fix unknowns with Excel
- * Added and removed floor locations to improve warehouse workflow
- * Performed cycle counts on Order Picker

Quality Auditor

UNFI, May 2017 – February 2019

- * Built auditing software to automatically detect mis-picks and document additional quality errors such as product hanging over pallets and liquids stacked on their sides.
- * Audited all outbound processes, including replenishment, picking, loading, and inbound.

Freelance Software Developer

Self-Employed, May 2017- June 2018

- * Created educational minigames in Unity3D and C# to aid in teaching AP Biology.
- * Combined the concepts of personality theory and microeconomics to assist in creating a sociological simulation game to help students maximize social cohesion and economic productivity by using JavaScript, NodeJS, HTML5, and CSS

ICQA Program Developer (Tier IV Associate)

Amazon, December 2016 – April 2017

- * Developed software to help more efficiently stow inventory.
- * Developed software to automate Excel reports and help managers communicate safety issues.

Tier I Associate

Amazon, March 2015 - December 2016

- * Worked every Tier 1 position in the warehouse in every department and every process.
- * Was stationed as Problem Solver by both Inbound and Outbound and was eventually promoted to a Tier IV position.

Unity 3D / Android Developer

Vision Three Creative, LLC, March 2014 - October 2014

- * Constructed the user interface of a custom Android application used to control an embedded medical device
- * Updated and maintained applications for a large client base
- * Originated demonstrations of AR and VR applications for clients

Freelance Software Developer

Self-Employed, May 2011 – July 2014

- * Developed AI and pathfinding solutions for all game enemies in Dreamland Delivery using A* and B-Splines in C# for Puca Studios
- * Produced educational Flash games for the Indianapolis Children's Museum